ULYSSES FIGUEROA

FULL STACK DEVELOPER







Gilbert, AZ

EDUCATION

FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT

University of Arizona

2019 - Present

BIOLOGY

Chandler Gilbert Community

College, Arizona

2012 - 2013

HARD SKILLS

Programming:

 HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, MySQL, React, MongoDB, Github, Bootstrap, Materialize

CMS:

 Wordpress, Visual Studio, Atlasstian, Sharepoint

Microsoft:

 Word, Excel, Access, Powerpoint

SOFT SKILLS

Project Management

Analytical Thinking

Conflict Resolution

Team Leadership

Efficient Under Pressure

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Solutions-driven Full Stack Developer with a 4-year track record of exceptional performance in the hospitality industry. Experienced in web development, procurement, installation, and technical support. Resilient self-starter excels in identifying and resolving key issues, implementing new processes to improve workflows, and interdepartmental communication.

EXPERIENCE

LEAD PROGRAMMER

Kahala Management / Scottsdale, AZ / 2018 - current

Manage the creation, deployment and maintenance of all programming tasks across various point-of-sale systems. Interdepartmental collaborations and project management ensuring successful marketing products launched.

Responsible for 1100+ locations across 25 Brands

JR PROGRAMMER / IT SUPPORT / PURCHASING AGENT

Somi Data LLC / Chandler, AZ / 2015 – 2018

Repsonsible for providing technical support for various clients across multiple systems. Manage hardware, menu alterations, custom reporting, MDM systems, and database integrations. Collaborate with multiple departments to ensure maximum productivity. Website integrations, search engine optimizations, and upkeep.

- IT support and maintenance for 100+ Pinkberry locations.
- Create and implement procedures to streamline department workflow and increase efficiency.

OWNER

Medical Lien Management / Chandler, AZ / 2011 - 2015

Consulting, hiring, training, and developing various departments within the Workers' Compensation industry. Conducted audits and analyzed cost of high dollar portfolios in order to make recommendations and custom business plans for improvement. Offered billing, collections, and marketing to several physicians/medical groups of various specialties in addition to specialized Global settlements with several insurance companies.

References available upon request